Finding Aid for Raab family papers, ca.1830-1969
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Raab family papers circa 1830-1969
Raab family.
1 linear foot
85371 Aa 2
Michigan family from Adrian and Flint, Michigan. Family papers, sound recordings, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Harriet Raab Hill (donor no. 4854 ).
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Raab-Pomeroy-Zimmerman-Tomlinson families were residents of Adrian, Flint, and other cities. Irving T. Raab, was a Flint, Michigan clergyman who had attended the University of Michigan (class of 1900). His wife Florence Pomeroy Raab was also a graduate of the University of Michigan (class of 1898).
The collection is arranged by family name: Tomlinson, Pomeroy, and Raab. The earliest item is an account maintained by Alexander Tomlinson of Sherwood, Michigan. Within the Raab family papers are diaries, 1891-1892, of Florence Raab concerning her life in Adrian, Michigan. In addition, the collection includes papers and audio-tapes of Irving T. Raab reminiscing about his student life at the University of Michigan in the years before 1900. These tapes also concern his life in Flint and career as Presbyterian clergyman. The photographs in the collection are of family members.
Subjects:
Adrian (Mich.); Clergy--Michigan.; Flint (Mich.); Michigan--Social life and customs--1871-1880.; Michigan--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Presbyterian Church.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Women--Michigan--Adrian.; Michigan--Social life and customs--19th century.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Aged persons.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Lodging houses.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Streets.; Arizona.; Brown, Mabel.; Celebrations.; Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Dwellings.; East University Avenue (Ann Arbor, Mich.); First Presbyterian Church (Saline, Mich.); Interiors--1961-1970.; Lodging houses--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Pearce, Myrtis Raab.; Pomeroy, Francis Mills, 1840-1904.; Pomeroy, Susan Lincoln.; Pomeroy family.; Presbyterian churches--Michigan--Saline.; Raab, Alice Cary, 1873-1964.; Raab, Arthur E.; Raab, Ethel, 1882-1971.; Raab, George, 1845-; Raab, Harriet.; Raab, Irving T. (Irving Tomlinson), 1875-1969.; Raab, Margaret Lincoln.; Raab family.; Saline (Mich.)--Presbyterian churches.; South University Avenue (Ann Arbor, Mich.); State Street (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Tekonsha (Mich.); United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; University of Michigan--Campus--1901-1910.; Washtenaw Avenue (Ann Arbor, Mich.); West Engineering Building (University of Michigan); Women.; Women--Organizations.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Raab, Irving T. (Irving Tomlinson), 1875-1969.; Clergy--Michigan--Flint.; Flint (Mich.)--History.; University of Michigan--History.; University of Michigan--Students--Social life and customs--1891-1900.; Hill, Harriet Raab.
Contributors:
Pomeroy family.; Raab, Irving T. (Irving Tomlinson), 1875-1969.; Tomlinson family.; Zimmerman family.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Tomlinson family
  - Account book-notebook of Alexander Tomlinson of Sherwood (Branch County) circa 1830s (Box 1)
- Pomeroy family
  - Henry Martyn Pomeroy (Box 1)
  - Frances Mills Pomeroy
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
    - Diary, 1875 (Box 1)
      (concerns life in Adrian and Ohio)
- Raab family
  - George Raab
    - Miscellaneous papers 1875 (Box 1)
    - Papers concerning the capture of Jefferson Davis (Box 1)
  - Alice Cary Raab papers (Box 1)
  - Arthur E. Raab papers (Box 1)
  - Ethel Raab papers (Box 1)
  - Florence Pomeroy Raab
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
    - Diaries, 1891-1892, 2 volumes (Box 1)
      (concerns life in Adrian)
    - Readings given by circa 1899 (Box 1)
  - Irving Tomlinson Raab
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous and other family members
  - Harriet Raab Hill Kelley papers (Box 1)
  - Mary Wood-Allen papers (Box 1)
  - Genealogical material (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea (Box 1)
- Sound recordings
  - Interview conducted by his daughter Harriet Raab Hill December 8, 1965, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 1)
    (Raab reminiscences his years as a student at the University of Michigan, 1896-1900 other topics discussed include how Raab learned to think and to question, life at the boarding house of Mrs. Russell, the founding of the Y.M.C.A. in Ann Arbor, the Student Christian Association, and his impressions of professors Martin L. D'Ooge and Robert M. Wenley)
    (duplicate copy available)
  - Recording of 90th Birthday Celebration for Rev. Irving T. Raab December 12, 1965, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 1)
  - Recording of Rev. Irving T. Raab, questioned by Harriet Raab Hill January, 1996 and February 1966, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 1)
    (Topics discussed concern Flint, Michigan, 1885-1890 its businesses, downtown section, local personages, and its political structure.)
  - Recording of Rev. Irving T. Raab, questioned by Harriet Raab Hill February 1966, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 1)
    (Topics discussed concern Flint, Michigan in the 1880s particularly its schools, Hazelton House, economic conditions, and Court Street Methodist Church.)
  - Reminiscences of Rev. Irving T. Raab, questioned by Harriet Raab Hill, recorded in 1966, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 7 in. (Box 1)
    (Topics discussed include Raab's religious philosophy, and a few memories of the Union Theological Seminary, 1902-1904.)
  - Reminiscences of Rev. Irving T. Raab, and questioned by Harriet Raab Hill, recorded June 10, 1967, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips: 7 in. (Box 1)
    (Topics discussed include the transformation of Flint, Michigan since 1885 its first reliance on water power and its change to steam power and electricity.)
  - Recording of Rev. Irving T. Raab June 24, 1967, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 5 in. (Box 1)
    (Discussion of the site of the Flint Chevrolet plant; also include personal message to Ethel Raab)
  - Devotional remarks of Rev. Irving T. Raab to residents of Pitzer retirement home 1967, (1 sound tape reel: 3 3/4 ips; 5 in. (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Ann Arbor and University of Michigan views 1904 (Box 1)
  - Frances Mills Pomeroy (Mrs. Henry Martyn, 1840-1904) (Box 1)
  - Alice Cary Raab (1873-1964) (Box 1)
  - Arthur E. Raab (Box 1)
  - Ethel Raab (1882-1971) (Box 1)
  - Florence Pomeroy Raab (1875-1955) (Box 1)
  - George Raab (b. 1845-) (Box 1)
  - George Raab and Capture of Jefferson Davis (Box 1)
  - Irving T. Raab (1875-1969) (Box 1)
  - Mary Wood-Allen (medical doctor and friend of Florence Pomeroy Raab) (Box 1)